While most spider and scorpion bites cause only mild reactions like some redness and swelling,
certain venomous ones, like the black widow or brown recluse, can make someone very ill.
Small children and those with existing medical issues are at a higher risk for more severe
complications, so you'll want to keep a close eye on them. As you assess the person, watch for signs
like muscle cramps, fever, a headache, or more serious issues like difficulty breathing or
fainting. If you notice severe symptoms like trouble breathing, intense pain, or an altered
mental status, call 911 immediately. For most situations, your immediate care is to wash the
wound with soap and water and apply an ice pack to manage the discomfort. For children, it is always
a good idea to follow up by calling poison control or their healthcare provider for further guidance.
Finally, if you can do so safely and without touching the insect, try to take a photo of it.
This can be incredibly helpful for medical professionals to identify
exactly what caused the bite and determine the best treatment.